だっせ
これなんか可愛いぞ
ほら 見ろ雪音
マジでこんなの着んの
つべこべ言うな
じゃあ 俺着るよ
Am I seriously supposed to wear this?
Don't be so picky.
How about this one, Yukine?
It's pretty cute.
Capypa
Land
なんでこう生理現象は残ってんだ
How uncool...
Capypa
Land
I'll wear it then!
Why can I still feel physical things?
俺はもう とっくに死んでるってのに
Yuki
Even though I'm already dead...
弾丸込めた小銃を僕は片手に持っている
震えた君の居る場所へ　足を早め向かっている
（チクタク針をチクタクと）
焦る心を急かしただけ
留まる気配もなく進んでゆく
（チクタク針をチクタクと）
終わりと始まりの境目
全て重なった
Hey！どうして僕は待っていた
薄暗い部屋一人きり
ドアを蹴破るその音を
Hey！どうして僕は待っていた
薄暗い部屋一人きり
もう恐れることは無いよ
弾丸込めた小銃を持って
固く閉ざされたドアを蹴破った
吸い付いた銃口が跳ねて
昨日の僕を貫いた
上澄みそう絶望を受け取って
明日へと僕は歩き始めた
また今夜待ち合わせよう
本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigami.org)制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听:小然&千夜  翻译:maki&迩祢  校对:木落&叶隐  时间轴:Gissa  压制:久嘉
Café Restaurant
MOST
Cheeseburger IN
+rice
今日はここにするか
Well, let's eat here for today.
ほれ
Here.
何これ
What's this?
雪音が腹減ったっつうから
You said you were hungry, right?
昼飯食わせてやってんだろ
That's your lunch.
昼飯
This is... lunch?
お前が俺の神器
You are my Sacred Tool.
You must obey your master's orders!
主の言うことは絶対だ
神器ね
Sacred Tool, huh?
そう
That's right!
A Sacred Tool honors and respects his master...
神器とは 主人を敬い
奉り
and works as his hands and feet!
主人の手足となって働く
お茶汲むくらいの気を利かす
You should at least prepare some tea!
お茶入れようにも家ねえじゃん
How can I prepare tea when you don't even have a home?
口答えなんてもってのほか
I won't have you talk back at me! I command obedience!
従順であれ
いやー 禿げる
I'm going bald!
止めろ このクソ猫 こら
神って何すんのかと思えば
I never thought a god would live like this.
宛もなく街をふらふらして
All we do is wander the town aimlessly,
人目避けるように その辺のお堂の隅とかで小さくなって寝て
and sleep in the corner of some secluded, old shrine to avoid attention.
日用品はゴミの中から拾ったもんだし
We've even stooped low enough to look for food in the garbage.
Delivery God Yato
第一 それ何
Anyway, what's that?
布教活動
Missionary work!
全然依頼来ねえじゃん
As if we get any.
あんた本当に神なわけ
Are you really a god?
Why are you looking at me like that?
なんだよ その目
俺の力 見せてやるよ
Let me show you my power then.
Episode 3
Invited Disaster
いらっしゃいませ
Welcome!
ひよりが食いもん供えるってよ
Hiyori's getting us food as an offering!
What do you think of my charisma now!
どうよ このカリスマス
完全にたかりじゃん
This is completely an extortion.
食べたら 今度こそ私のお願い聞いてくださいよ
You better listen to my request when you're done.
Welcome!
いらっしゃいませ
お決まりになりましたら
Have you decided on your order?
お姉さん 水三つ
Miss, three glasses of water please.
も 申し訳ごさいません
I-I'm so sorry!
夜トたちは人間じゃないから 人に見えないのでは
I thought you guys were supposed to be invisible since you are not humans.
違う
Wrong.
俺たちは見えないんじゃなくて
It's not that we're invisible; it's just that we're hard to notice.
目に止まりにくいの
実際にゃ見えてる
In reality we're quite visible.
逆に聞くが
Let me put it this way.
How many waitresses are there in this restaurant?
ここのウエーイトレスは何人いた
おっと 見んなよ
Don't look.
えっと 二人
Let's see... two?
Huh, there are four?
あれ 四人
そういうこと
That's how it is.
俺と雪音はお前が見落とした二人のように
People overlook Yukine and me because we're always in their blind spots.
背景扱いなのさ
We're treated as humans the instant they recognize us,
一度認識されると 人として共有されるが
またすぐ忘れられる
but they also forget us just as quickly.
Please pardon me. Thank you for waiting!
大変失礼いたしました
You don't remember every single person you walk past everyday, right?
Cheeseburger IN
+rice
+soup
ひよりだって 今まで街ですれ違った人間
全て覚えちゃいねえだろ
俺たちは彼岸の住人だから
That's especially the case for us since we're from Nirvana.
なおさらな
そのわりには よく召し上がりますね
And yet, you really eat a lot, don't you?
Never let an offering go to waste!
お供え物は残さない
これ 絶対
That is absolute!
お腹壊しますよ
You'll upset your stomach, you know?
大丈夫
Worry not! Gods don't poop.
神様うんこしない
Café Restaurant
MOST
Cheeseburger IN
+rice
+soup
ありがとうごさいました
Thank you very much!
Café Restaurant
MOST
もう 全くあの人は
Seriously!
He gets on my nerves!
Café Restaurant
MOST
一応 ごちそうさん
Anyway, thanks for treating us.
いえいえ
No problem.
私 壱岐ひより
My name is Iki Hiyori.
ひよりでいいよ
You can just call me Hiyori, okay?
ひよりはあれの何
So what's your relation to that thing, Hiyori?
Well, I easily lose my body because of an incident,
えっと 体を落とす体質になっちゃったから
この飴全部くれ
I can take as many of these sweets as I want, right?
あのう
I mean, why can't I? They're free after all, aren't they?
どうして
夜トに治してもらいたくて
so I want Yato to fix it.
ただでしょ　ただなんでしょう
Man, sucks to be you.
ついてないね
だよね
You can say that again...
あのう 雪音君は何で
Yukine-kun, why are you...
夜トの神器になる前は どうしてたの
How were you before becoming Yato's Sacred Tool?
さあ
No clue.
Yuki
とにかく 死んだのは知ってるけど
Somehow, I knew I was already dead,
Yuki
but the next thing I knew, I was in his hand.
気付いたら あいつの手の中にいて
生きてた時のことは 全く覚えてない
I don't remember anything from when I was still alive.
これからのことも さっぱり
I have no clue what I'm gonna do from now on.
MOST
Café Restaurant
Cheeseburger IN
+rice
+soup
お前 さっきの目刺し泥棒
Hey, aren't you the food thief from earlier?
There, there...
よしよし
MOST
雪音君 ネコ好きなの
Yukine-kun, do you like cats?
MOST
多分
Probably.
可愛いよね ネコ
Cats are cute, aren't they?
私も好き
I like them too.
Yukine!
雪音 お前今エロいこと考えたろ
Did you just have a perverted thought?
Listen here, Yukine.
いいか 雪音 教えとくぞ
神と神器は一心同体なの
A god and his Sacred Tool are one body and soul!
As your master, I can pick up every dark thought that crosses your mind!
Café Restaurant
MOST
お前の邪な心の波は
主人である俺に 伝わっちまうんだからな
Huh? What are you talking about?
何言ってんだこいつ
あのう 一心同体ってどういう
Um, what do you mean by "one body and soul"?
Café Restaurant
Man, kids going through puberty really are troublesome, aren't they?
まったく
Café Restaurant
思春期のお子ちゃまには 困りもんでちゅねえ
うっさい ボケ
Shut up, you idiot!
Who's the idiot here?!
ボケとは何だ
お前に俺の何が分かったよ
あんなんて 本当に人の願いを聞く神様 なの
Is that really a god who grants people wishes?
やるのか このエロガキが
マジうっせいよ
はい
Yes, this is the fast, cheap, and safe Delivery God Yato at your service!
早くて安くて安心 デリバリーゴッドの夜トでございます
雪音 仕事だ すぐ行くぞ
Yukine, it's a job!
Let's go!
A job?
仕事
What?! W-Wait!
ちょっと 私の依頼は
What about my request?!
ひっひっふー
お前まで来ちまったのかよ
You came along too?
文句あるなら 私の体質何とかしてください
If you're gonna complain, then fix my current problem first!
尻尾
A tail?!
何もんだ
Who goes there?!
依頼のふりして ハメやがったな
You tricked me with a fake request, didn't you?!
東風吹かば
"When the east wind blows, flourish in full bloom, you, plum blossoms!"
匂いおこせよ 梅の花
う 梅が
The plum blossoms!
主人なしとて 春を忘るな
"Even though you lose your master, don't be oblivious to spring."
Th-This poem is "Sugawara no Michizane"!
こ この歌は菅原道真
もしかして
Don't tell me...
You're the god of learning, Lord Tenjin?
学問の神 天神様
あれ 分かっちゃった
Hm?
You figured it out?
神よ
O God!
You certainly know quite a bit, don't you, little spirit?
そこの生霊ちゃん よく知ってるね
結構な懐メロよ
It is quite an old poem.
教科書に載ってます
It's listed in our textbooks!
Oh dear. What's happened to those copyright laws?
困るな 著作権はどうなってるの
没後50年までです
It expired 50 years after your death!
あらそう
Ah, is that so?
すっげー神オーラ
What an awesome godly aura!
格好しすぎます
It's so divine!
あらあら そう
Oh my, is that so?
それに引き換え
Compared to this...
Hm?
夜ト君
Yato-kun, what is this boy's name?
この子名前は
His name is Yuki.
名は雪（ゆき） 器は雪（せつ）
His weapon is snow.
呼び名は雪音だ
You can call him Yukine.
Yukine-kun, you just became
a Sacred Tool recently, didn't you?
雪音君 君神器に成り立てだね
神器は平伏せずともよいのだよ
As a Sacred Tool, you don't need to prostrate yourself.
Huh?
梅雨
Tsuyu.
そうじゃ
Indeed, young boy.
良いか 坊
己が仕える神の手前にて 他の神に平伏すは
It is impolite to bow before other gods, when you are serving one yourself.
礼を欠くこととなる
覚えておくが良い
It'd be best to keep that in mind.
Wow!
すごい
やっぱり巫女さんも沢山いらっしゃるんですね
You really do have a lot of shrine maidens with you!
I'm Ayu.
歩喩です
I'm Nayu.
南喩です
I'm Miyu.
実喩です
望喩です
And I'm Moyu.
私たち
Together, we are... the Tenjin Sisters!
天神シスターズです
Well, those girls are my Sacred Tools.
彼女たちはまあ みんな僕の神器だよ
養うだけでも大変さ
It's hard to take care of them.
本物の神様は違います
Real gods are totally different after all!
I'm a real god too!
俺も本物だ
で 要件は
So what's your business?!
Ah, you know how I'm busy with the exam season approaching and all?
僕今忙しいじゃない
Please let me pass
my high school exams
Please let me graduate high school
together with my friends
受験シーズンで
There's a certain Ayakashi that I want you to take care of.
ちょっと斬って欲しいあやかしがいるんだよね
君 どうせ暇でしょ
You're free anyway, right?
うちのお社で勝手に寝泊まりしてるの知ってるよ
I do notice that you sleep at my shrine, you know?
You're welcome to join my Tenman Group if you want.
いいんだよ
うちの天満グループに入れてやっても
支店長にしてあげるよ
I can make you a branch manager.
でもさ
But then again, you want your own shrine, right?
君 自分のお社欲しいんでしょう
だったら ほら
Then...
Oh, sorry. I only have large bills.
ごめん  大きいのしかなかった
お釣りある
Do you have any change?
Oh my, you don't have enough, do you?
おや 足りないのかな
The gap between the rich and the poor exists even amongst the gods.
こんな所にまで 貧富の差が
だから世の中不公平なんだな
That's why the world's unfair, huh?
You do have change!
持ってんじゃねえか
では 案内を頼んだよ
Well then, I'll leave you to show him the way, Makoto.
真
Makoto
My lord, Mayu just became your Sacred Tool recently and lacks experience.
公 真喩はここに来て日も浅く
Will you not consider the others?
案内はほかの者に
うん けどね
True, but she also knows Yato-kun very well.
真喩は夜ト君のこと　よく知ってるんだ
偽物じゃねえだろうな
This better not be fake.
伴音
Tomone?!
Noragami
N
o
r
a
g
m
My name is not Tomone,
i
伴音ではありません
it's Mayu.
真喩です
Tomone, what are you
doing in a shrine like this?
伴音　お前
こんな大手に
My name is Mayu!
真喩です
Excuse me...
あの
I used to be Yato-san's Sacred Tool.
私　前は夜トさんの神器だったんです
Is that so?!
そうだったんですか
What was he like to work with?
どうでした　お仕事のほうは
Did he manage to complete requests properly?
ちゃんと依頼はこなしてましたか
What about clothing, food, and other accommodations?
衣食住のほうは
Is he really just a homeless,
unemployed, jersey-wearing guy?
あいつ　本当に住所不定無職のジャージー
He was a homeless, unemployed,
jersey-wearing man who called himself a god.
住所不定無職の　自分は神だと言うジャージーの人でした
Stand up a little for your former master, Tomone!
少しは元主をたてろ　伴音
It's Mayu!
真喩です
Please don't call me by my old name.
昔の名前で呼ばないで　汚らわしい
It's disgusting!
You used to say you felt disgusted when I touched you,
俺に触られるのがどうとか言ってたくせに
yet you've become this old man's smoking pipe!
爺の煙管なんか成り上がって
Did you get blinded by money?!
金に目が眩んだか
I'm fine anywhere as long as it's not with you!
あんたのとこじゃなきゃどこだっていいわ
Um, ex-girlfriend?
も　元カノさん
No!
違う
Ex-wife, then?
元嫁か　相当拗れたな
Looks like things got really sour...
I keep telling you you're wrong!
だから違うって
Either way, you both are totally on bad terms...
どっちにしろ拗れせてるじゃねえか
おい　伴音
汚らわしいとは何事だ
Excuse me.
あの
訴えてやる 法廷で会おう
この野郎
Your request for Yato is to
exterminate an Ayakashi, right?
夜トヘの依頼って　あやかし退治なんですよね
Is it wrong for Ayakashi to exist?
あやかしってそんなに悪い存在なんですか
Why do they have to be exterminated?
何でやっつけなくちゃいけないんでしょうか
"If man awakens, so does heaven."
人が荒めば天も荒む
Hiyori-san, is it?
ひよりさんといったかね
I don't think it's a good idea for you to concern yourself too much with our matters.
余りこちら側にかかわるのは感心しないね
You will easily interfere with whatever is between your world and ours.
僕らと人は干渉しやすい
A few days ago, we received a rather unsettling request.
先日
I want to
graduate from
university for
my friends
who are in
heaven now.
Natsuki
ちょっと気になる絵馬が奉納されましたので
Upon further investigation,
I want to
graduate from
university for
my friends
who are in
heaven now.
Natsuki
調べてみましたら
It seems that two people have already died here.
既に二人もなくなっているそうです
How could such a thing happen?
なんでそんなこと
This route is often stormy.
この辺りはよく時化ます
People become possessed by Ayakashi when they succumb to temptation.
寄ってきたあやかしに取り付かれ　魔が差すのでしょう
Michizane-sama erected a barrier here after hearing the hurt of the students' hearts,
お心を痛められた道真さんもここに結界を張るなどなさったのですが
but people tend to carry deeply-rooted darkness in their hearts,
人は魔を内に秘めたまま出入りするので
making complete purification difficult.
完全な浄化は難しくて
Life is so precious...
尊い命なのに
How wasteful...
もったいないですよね
In that case, we just need to defeat the Ayakashi that's been possessing people here, right?
では　その人に取り付くあやかしを倒せばいいんですね
That's right.
はい
Hiyori?
ひより
People are dying here!
人がなくなってるんですよ
Don't you think we should do something?
何とかしたいと思いませんか
If people want to die, let them die.
死にたいやつは死ねばいい
What?
You're still as vile as ever!
相変わらず何というくず
Don't you think that was an awful thing to say?
あの　今の言い方はないんじゃないですか
Souls with suicidal tendencies are already tainted.
自殺するような魂は既に魔に取り付かれてるから
They can't even become a Sacred Tool.
神器にもなれねえ
Whether they're dead or alive, there's no saving them.
もう死んだやつも　まだ生きてるやつも
救いようがない
N-No way!
そ　そんな
Isn't it your job to save them?!
それがあなたの仕事でしょ
Well, I'll be going now.
さあ　けんべ
Hold it!
お待ち　前金
You've been paid in advance!
Is it all right to leave her by herself?
いいのかよ
一人で行かせて
That guy's really...
あいつって本当に
Yukine, this is your first job.
雪音
初仕事だ
What do I have to do?
俺は何をすれば
Come when I call out your weapon,
「器」を呼んだら来い
and return when I call out your name.
「名」を呼んだら戻れ
That's all for now.
今はそれでいい
Yato...
夜ト
If people want to die, then let them die.
死にたいやつは死ねばいい
You really are the worst!
あなたって最低
Passing
Local
Shinki-Ba Station
10 cars 4 doors
I really don't want to work,
まだ　働きたくねえけど
but it's not like I want to go to college either.
別に大学に行ってもやりたいことないし
Sushi roll... kick!
寿司ロールキック
I won't stand for anything that makes people do terrible things!
人について悪さする子は許しません
なんだあれは
One of us...? One of us?
仲間
仲間半分
The next train will be arriving on Platform 1.
Let's get her to join us... one of us... let's take her...
一番ホームまもなく電車が通り過ぎます
連れて行こう
Please stand behind the yellow line.
黄色い線の内側でお待ちください
そうだね
こちらに連れて行こう
Come over here... Come...
おいで　おいで
ちょっ
Jump!
飛べ
Are you okay?
大丈夫か
Jeez.
ったく
Didn't I say you'd be dead if your tail got cut?!
尻尾が切れたら死ぬっつっただろ
Just stay put here.
おとなしくそこにいろ
Yukine,
雪音　この先の踏み切りが本番だ
we're reaching the crucial railway crossing from earlier.
I got an E for my first subject...
第一志望E判定
ああ　まずいよこれ
This is bad...
E... E...
E　いい
Eee's fine... Eet's fine, innit?
いいじゃん　いいじゃん
Eet's fine if you come this way.
こっちにこればいいじゃん
It's fine... It's totally fine...
いいよ　いいよ
It's fine... It's fine... It's fine...
いいよ
I guess... it's fine.
いいかな
いいよ いいよ
We're going to cut that Ayakashi.
あのあやかしを斬る
Don't get cold feet now, Yukine.
ビビんなよ　雪音
Piece of cake.
余裕
It's fine... It's fine...
いいよ　いいよ
We're not gonna make—
だめだ　間に合わ
We will!
せる
いいよ
It's okay...
I beseech thee, all things sacred.
豊葦原の中津国
荒び足らせぬ「彼」のものよ
in my name, Yatogami,
我夜ト神来たり降り
bearing Sekki as my arm, I shall crush all evil,
雪器を以って砕きふせ
種々の障り穢れを打ち払わん
and purify all manner of evil and filth!
Rend!
斬
Yuki, it's okay now!
雪　もういい 戻れ
Return!
Yuki
You cut too much!
お前は斬りすぎる
Yuki
Even after you said that people who wanted to die should just die,
死にたいやつは死ねばいいなんていってたけど
you still saved him.
やっぱり助けてくれるんですね
That's not the point.
そうなんじゃねえよ
It's just that I don't want these guys to see them die like this.
だが　こいつらの前で軽々しく死なせたりしねえ
"These guys"?
こいつら
Even when times get dark and painful,
苦しくても　つらくても
people should feel lucky to be alive at all.
生きていられる重みを感じやがれってんだ
Souls with suicidal tendencies are already tainted.
自殺するような魂は既に魔に取り付かれてるから
They can't even become a Sacred Tool.
神器にもなれねえ
Every one of them is so young.
皆　あんなに若く幼い
If it wasn't suicide, then that means...
自殺ではないということは
Sacred Tools are people who still wanted to live.
神器はまだ生きたかった人たち
For them to witness other people wasting their lives before their eyes...
そんな人たちの前で
命を粗末にする人間を 夜トは許せなかったんだ
was something Yato couldn't forgive.
Hiyori?
ひより
Yukine, you perv!
エロ雪音
D-Did you do something to her?
お前　何かしたのか
I did not!
してねえ
I-I'm fine. I just got some dust from the debris in my eyes.
だい　大丈夫です
ちょっとさっきの粉々が目に入っただけ
That's not fine at all!
それ　全然大丈夫じゃ…
Don't rub your eyes!
目擦るな
Stay calm, Hiyori!
ひより　冷静になれ
At times like these, take deep breaths!
こういう時はいいか　深呼吸しろ
ひっひっふーだ
Will that really help her?
それで助かんのか
Wear this.
使え
It should make you feel warmer.
少しは暖かいだろ
Capypa
Land
You did quite well for your first job today.
今日はまぁ
初めてにしちゃ　なかなかいい仕事ぶりだった
君の名前 何があっても
必ず呼ぶから
君はぎざぎざハートの持ち主
触れるものは何でも傷つけ
世界のすべてを睨み付けて
その目は言うんだ
「僕はここにいる」
誰かが笑ってた
だから引いたんだ その境界線
それなら
私はその手を引く
さぁ
連れてくから
言えないなら
この手を強く握って
離さないで
君はもう一人じゃないんだって
知ってほしいんだよ
Yukine, do you know the difference between butter and margarine?
雪音　バターとマーガリンの違いは分かるか
Th-The ingredients are different?
ざい　材料の違いとか
Wrong!
The names are different!
ぶぶ　名前が違います
You can't even answer such a simple quiz question?
こんな簡単な謎なぞも分かんねえのか
Next time on Noragami: "The Place of Happiness."
次回 ノラガミ
しあわせの在処
You're really annoying, Yato!
Next Episode
The Place of Happine
夜トまじうぜえ
Endure it, Yukine-kun!
ファイト　雪音君